Buffalo Corrugated Container Company-Fibre Factory Company Records
Buffalo History Museum. Research Library
Buffalo Corrugated Container Company-Fibre Factory Company Records
1912 - 1947
Company records for the Buffalo Corrugated Container Company-Fibre Factory.
3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
Buffalo Corrugated Container Company (N.Y.).
The Buffalo History Museum 1 Museum Court Buffalo, NY 14216 Phone: 716-873-9644 ext. 306 Fax: 716-873-8754 Email: library@buffalohistory.org URI: http://www.buffalohistory.org
Mss. B94-1
Organized into three series: I. Buffalo Corrugated Container Company, 1912-1947, subseries A-B as follows: A. Tax records, 1912-1945; B. Insurance records, 1941-1947. II. Buffalo Corrugated Container Company- Fibre Factory Company income tax returns, 1917-1921. III. Fibre Factory Company, 1913-1944, subseries A-B as follows: A. Tax records, 1913-1943; B. Insurance records, 1944. Chronological arrangement within series.
Donated by Susan M. Rathwell. Accession number 94-75
Researchers wishing to access this collection must apply for a Scholar Pass and present valid photo ID upon arrival to the library.
Founded in 1910 by William A. and Harley N. Sickler, and Charles G. Moore, as a manufacturer and seller of corrugated paper and paper board containers and packing boxes. The company was located at 25-39 Imson Street, Buffalo, N.Y.
Fibre Factory Company was formed in 1914 as a holding company for the purpose of buying and maintaining a factory building for the Buffalo Corrugated Container Company.
Buffalo Corrugated Container Company became a subsidiary of Jefferson Smurfit Corporation ca. 1985, was renamed Mohawk Containers, and moved to Pearl and Central Streets, Lancaster, N.Y., taking over a plant formerly occupied by Diamond International. In October, 1993, Jefferson Smurfit closed the local operation.
Paper box industry New York (State) Buffalo.; insurance records; tax records; Fibre Factory Company (Buffalo, N.Y.).
Tax and insurance records, 1912-1947, for Buffalo Corrugated Container Company and Fibre Factory Company, a holding company.
- Buffalo Corrugated Container Company, 1912 - 1947; I
  - Tax records, 1912 - 1945; A
    - Correspondence, 1918 - 1945 (Box-folder 1.1-1.3)
    - Corporation income tax returns, 1912 - 1945 (Box-folder 1.4-1.9)
    - Returns of capital-stock tax, 1918 - 1945 (Box-folder 1.10)
    - Annual returns of excise tax, 1936 - 1945 (Box-folder 1.11)
    - Employer’s tax returns, 1938 - 1945 (Box-folder 2.1)
    - Annual information returns, 1918 - 1945 (Box-folder 2.2)
    - Census of manufactures, 1925 - 1939 (Box-folder 2.3)
    - Inventory and return: cotton, paper, and jute, 1933 (Box-folder 2.4)
    - New York State franchise tax, 1918 - 1944 (Box-folder 2.5)
    - Returns of taxes on retail sales, 1933 - 1934 (Box-folder 2.6)
    - Payroll reports, 1936 - 1945 (Box-folder 2.7)
    - Annual summaries and letters of transmittal, 1933 - 1944 (Box-folder 2.8)
  - Insurance records, 1941 - 1947; B
    - General liability policies, 1941 - 1947 (Box-folder 2.9)
    - Workmen’s compensation and employer’s liability policies, 1941 - 1947 (Box-folder 2.10)
    - Automotive policies, 1942 - 1946 (Box-folder 2.11)
    - Equipment policies, 1945 (Box-folder 2.12)
- Insurance records, 1941 - 1947; II
  - Corporation income tax returns, 1917 - 1921 (Box-folder 3.1-3.2)
- Fibre Factory Company, 1913 - 1944; III
  - Tax Records, 1913 - 1943; A
    - Correspondence, 1922 - 1925 (Box-folder 3.3)
    - Corporation income tax returns, 1913 - 1943 (Box-folder 3.4-3.8)
    - Returns of capital-stock tax, 1919 - 1943 (Box-folder 3.9)
    - New York State franchise tax, 1918 - 1942 (Box-folder 3.10)
    - Annual information returns, 1933 - 1939 (Folder 3.11)
  - Insurance Records, 1944; B
    - Building policy, 1944 (Box-folder 3.12)